

BENOY V N
Shalem, Nedinjal
Kalliyoor P O
Trivandrum, 695042

SNAPSHOT

Graduate with 6 years of experience in IT sector as Team Lead/Project Coordinator. And 3 year experience in Administration, Purchase, inventory management and in Logistics. Offering an exceptional ability to work under high pressure. Committed to quality performance with an ability to learn new procedures quickly. Combine organizational, multitasking and communication skills with the ability to plan and manage relationships.

E-mail: VN.BENOY@LIVE.COM

Phone: +91 9539 311 644

OBJECTIVE

To be the vital part of a reputed organization where my knowledge and willingness to work hard can be utilized in a manner, which is most beneficial for the organization and my career.

COMPETENCIES

Admin/Coordinator/Team Leader

- Office management, Coordinating office activities and operations, supervising administrative staff and dividing responsibilities.
- Supports human resources processes by administering tests, scheduling appointments, conducting orientation, maintaining records and information, coordinating appointments, provides payroll information, employee information by entering and updating employment and status-change data, Maintains quality service by following organization standards.
- Involved in Coordinating projects from inception to completion, made sure that deliverables are aligned with goals and objectives requested.
- Track and report project progress and made sure that strategy, goals and objectives are stated.
- Assisting and supporting the Project Manager, organizing project work and controlling schedule.

Team Leader / Document specialist

- Formatting documents and presentations using HTML, word and PPT, E-books production, Data organization and storage knowledge, Generate and update Databases, implementing SOP's for functional improvement and to meet the customer requirements.
- Finalizing tasks in fast deadline driven environment. Have superior organizational and analytical skills, Monitors and reports project and/or team performance against specific goals and objectives, ensuring that the project is delivered on time.

Purchase Executive/ Inventory and Logistics

- Document Management, Monitor and ensure joining loads and arriving loads, Maintaining Office Records, Sorting and Delivering Mail, Ordering Office Supplies, Preparation of stock inventory.
- Negotiation skills, Time management, Produce and maintain all reports, Record keeping and manage all documentation to confirm proper stock levels and maintain inventory control, Customer service, Vendor management, Office coordination, Quality evaluation and Estimation.

COMPUTER SKILLS Excellent skills in Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, OS Installation, Presentations, Database Administration, Outlook mail, expert in FTP, Acrobat, HTML and CSS.

EDUCATION

DEGREE IN BSC COMPUTER SCIENCE

2005-2008

Kerala University

HIGHER STUDIES 2003-2005

Kerala University

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

3DBRICKS, TRIVANDRUM

July-2018 - Present

Administrator

- Customer Service.
- Ensure Labor & Site staff attendance daily basis.
- Supervising administrative staff and dividing responsibilities to ensure performance.
- Organized and coordinated information and requirements; planning, arranging, and work schedules; monitoring results.
- Ensuring site material stocked and Track stocks of site supplies and place orders when necessary after Coordinating with internal departments like Civil Purchase, Accounts etc.
- Monitored & facilitation of servicing and repairing of assets as per maintenance schedules & register. Maintenance of all company assets and infrastructure.
- Communicate up-to-date information and deal with all colleagues in a courteous, efficient manner, Utmost honestly and sincerity is mandatory.
- Supervising day to day site operations and staff members.
- Preparation and maintenance of necessary records and files for billing and payment facilitation.

AL MAZHAR, SHARJAH – UAE

Oct 2016 - Feb 2018

Admin Executive/Purchase

- Customer Service
- Maintain records of goods ordered and received and Collate purchase orders and purchase requisitions in order to order materials, goods and supplies.
- Locate vendors of materials, equipment or supplies, and interview them in order to determine product availability and terms of sales.
- Direct and coordinate activities of businesses or departments concerned with the production, pricing, sales, or distribution of products.
- Documentation and data entry for all shipments including assisting logistic manager with daily functions.
- Submit timely reports and prepare presentations/proposals as assigned.
- Setting daily/weekly/monthly objectives and communicating them to production employees.
- Keep track of particular projects to meet the deadline and organizing workflow by assigning responsibilities and preparing schedules.

UNBOUND GLOBAL SERVICES PVT LTD, INDIA

Team Leader

- Supervised an IT team of 15-20 people.
- Coordinated different production teams.
- Interacting with clients through mails, chat and phone calls to solve queries and to time management.
- Managed outsourcing suppliers and Monitored and improved production team ability.
- Drafted reports and worked with the management team and Ensured deadlines were successfully met.
- Implemented SOP's for improving the production and Review assignments for accuracy and quality.
- Solved errors and motivated the team, produced attendance report, quality report, job tracking sheet etc.
- Giving direction and guidance also Develop and execute company policies.
- Deal with work pressure and carry out multiple assignments in a pre-scheduled timeframe.
- E-books and graphics projects outsourcing, tracking vendors and monitor the status of various projects.
- Collaborated with project Managers to develop focused plans and solutions.
- Monitored staff member work and prioritized tasks according to company objectives.

APTARA LEARNING PRIVATE LIMITED, INDIA

2010 Apr-2013 May

Team Leader

- Document formatting using HTML, MS word and PPT.
- Managed a team with 8-10 employees.
- Interacted with clients and completed jobs in the deadline.
- Implemented SOP's for improving the production.
- Produced quality report, job tracking sheet etc
- Prepared documents for in-house purpose and for clients.

PERSONAL PROFILE

Name BENOY V N
DOB 09-11-1987
Status Married

Languages English, Hindi, Malayalam, Tamil

Permanent Address Shalem, Nedinjal, Kalliyoor PO, Trivandrum

Kerala-695042

Contact number +91 9539 311 644 E-mail vn.benoy@live.com

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that all the information furnished above is true to the best of my belief.